<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maximum Recurstion Depth</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 16:15:23 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 16:15:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>

    
      <item>
        <title>A case for natrual primary keys</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Surrogate keys are a popular method for primary keys in a database. However, there is often a better way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all relational databases, there must be a way to uniquely identify every row of data. This job falls to the primary
 key, one column (or set of columns) per table that uniquely represents that row. You cannot have two rows with the same
 primary key. These keys are not only used by the database to organize and lookup data for the table, but are usually
 used as foreign keys, that is a reference from one table to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using randomly assigned ID’s is a popular method for creating primary keys on a database. These can take many forms,
 such as auto-incrementing integers or randomly generated UUID’s. These keys are then inserted into the table (or
 generated by it) for every row, making it uniquely identifiable. These are also called Surrogate keys and there are
 several reasons that are stated for using them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If using UUID’s, you can know your primary key before you insert the row, saving a round-trip to fetch it. This is
especially useful for many ORM’s that need the primary key value to work properly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is easy. Surrogate keys just happen automagically, meaning you don’t have to think about uniqueness of your data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both methods guarantee every row is unique, you don’t have to worry about duplicating data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, a Natural key is one that can be derived from the data. It may be one column of your existing data that
 is always unique (such as stock ticker or social security number), a combination of columns known as a composite key
 (such as name and address), or a hash of several columns into a new column. This means your data is naturally providing
 a unique key, hence the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many advantages of natural keys over surrogate keys, mainly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If using composite keys, there is no extra storage for a surrogate key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural keys can be computed, therefore there is no round-trip fetch to get them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They force data to be unique in the database, no accidental duplication of data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They can be calculated again and again, meaning rebuilding your data doesn’t cause them to be lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When build uploading data, foreign keys to other tables can be calculated, meaning you don’t have to look them up
at the time you insert new data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;natural-key-advantages&quot;&gt;Natural Key Advantages&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May database designers seem to shun natural keys nowadays. This probably has something to do with the wide use of ORM
systems that generally prefer to use auto-incrementing ID’s by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the use of natural keys can provide some major benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;natural-keys-can-be-computed&quot;&gt;Natural keys can be computed&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a primary key is computed before the row is inserted to the table, there is no round-trip fetch necessary to get
the primary key back. This round-trip fetch is necessary for ORM systems to properly represent the row, for setting up
foreign key relationships for example. Leaving the key assignment to the database means always fetching the value back,
which is a waste of a network call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;prevent-data-duplication&quot;&gt;Prevent data duplication&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this could go either way, many types of data shouldn’t be duplicated in a database. You wouldn’t want two
customers, two products, or two subscriptions in your database. With surrogate keys, there is no prevention of data
duplication. Of course, one could use UNIQUE constraints to prevent data duplication, but that is an extra step. The
constraints could be altered or lost over time and that would lead to duplication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the data with a natrual key bakes the uniqueness directly in to each row, there is no need for an extra step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;repeatability&quot;&gt;Repeatability&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As natural keys are built from the data, they will always be the same. If a data table needs to be deleted or rebuilt,
the keys will remain the same. With UUID’s or auto-incrementing integers, the keys would be randomly assigned if the
table is rebuilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While primary keys shouldn’t necessarily be used as ID’s outside the context of the database, they oftentimes get used
that way. With changing primary keys after a rebuild, any external system using them would be broken. With computed
keys, this is not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;calculate-foreign-keys&quot;&gt;Calculate foreign keys&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When bulk inserting a lot of data that has foreign keys, you need a way to get those keys. Let’s look at an example. Say
you have a table that holds product data, such as name, model number, description, etc. Then you have another table that
holds manufacturer information such as name, address, etc. Each product has a manufacturer and you link the two tables
with a foreign key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try upserting large amounts of data for different products and manufacturers, you would have to check if the
corresponding manufacturer exists in the database, and create it if not. Then you would have to look up the
corresponding manufacturer when you go to insert the products so you can get the proper foreign key. This requires many
queries to the database to fetch the manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, if you can calculate the primary key for the manufacturer, then you can simply build all the product rows
and insert them without having to query the manufacturing table at all. This makes inserting data much easier and
faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;natural-key-disadvantages&quot;&gt;Natural Key Disadvantages&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are, of course, some drawbacks to natural keys. Mainly,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your data needs to have an inherent uniqueness, which isn’t always the case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you need to change the data, you must change the key as it is derived from the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While choosing a primary key should always be done in the context of your data, using surrogate keys seems to be
overused in many places. This is probably due to the ease of use out of the box, especially when using ORM systems.
However, natural keys can provide a lot of benefits and should be considered. Being able to derive the key directly
from your data usually means less storage, less roud-trips to your database, and more consistency over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/17/a-case-for-natural-primary-keys/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/04/17/a-case-for-natural-primary-keys/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bring Your Kickstarter Dream to Reality</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://livefreeandstart.com/crowdfunding/bring-your-kickstarter-dream-to-reality/&quot;&gt;Live Fee and Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re funded! Or not…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not, don’t get too discouraged. Our first Kickstarter campaign failed to reach our goal. Instead of giving up, we went back to the drawing board and tried to find the problem. For us, it was a crappy video (see, our advice comes from experience!) and lack of a final design; we had a glove that didn’t even have our logo on it. We went out, re-did our campaign, and were successful on the second launch. I would say failing the first time was the single, biggest contributor to our success in subsequent campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you do get funded, you need to create whatever it is you promised. That is obviously specific to your project, so we won’t dive into too many details here. However, the one thing we will say, and this is critical, is that you need to be 100% transparent with your backers. They just gave you money for something that doesn’t exist; they bought in hard to your dream. You owe these people frequent (i.e. monthly) updates and pure honesty. Backers may get upset at delays or the limitations of your finished product, but they will be downright mutinous if you go silent on them. Being open and honest is a much easier path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we sum up, here are a few more tips and tricks we learned along the way. The first is something we warmly refer to as “blood sucking leaches.” These are the people who reach out to campaigns like yours and make promises to “get your name to 10,000 journalists and media contacts” or “in front of 100,000 relevant Twitter followers.” In general, these people just want your money. They should be avoided at all costs. Yes, they may have a long list of journalist emails, but it probably won’t help you. Your time and money are much better spent finding relevant journalists to your project and sending them personal emails. Blasting the heck out of a big list won’t get you anywhere. If anything, you may get in trouble. We learned this when our MailChimp account suspended, and Kickstarter threatened to suspend us for unsolicited emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, press and journalists won’t help you as much as you’d like. The only thing they care about is getting readers to their publication, so they will do this however they see fit. That may or may not include your project. They also have deadlines and other articles they need to write, plus getting 1,000 email pitches every day. Nearly all of them will ignore you. All that said, you still need to plug away and try to get a few good stories. Even one can pay off big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are funded, you will also have a large following of people who want to share in your idea. These people are the best customers you will ever have; they gave you money before you had anything. You need to setup a system to nurture that community as fast as possible. As good as Kickstarter is in some things, this is not one of them. We recommend setting up a community forum or other relevant site so you can have discussions and gather feedback. There are a lot of great tools to do this. Discourse is a forums software that we use, for example. Whatever you use, be sure to have somewhere outside of Kickstarter where you can grow and interact with this community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a logistical standpoint, once you are funded, you won’t get the money for two weeks. You will also lose 8% of it (5% to Kickstarter plus 3% to Amazon Payments), and you will probably have another 1%-2% lost to declined credit card transactions. Plan for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, once you are funded, you may need to contact your backers to ask them questions. (What size t-shirt? What color? Etc.). Kickstarter has a terrible system for this. We highly recommend using a separate survey system; we used one called BackerKit. It seems expensive, but because it allows your backers to buy more stuff, it usually pays for itself. We got about 10% additional funds on one of our Kickstarter campaigns solely by using BackerKit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, we hope you find yourself on your way to creating your own projects and campaigns, and that this little series helps in some way. We are happy to share what we have learned so far. If we ever do another campaign, we may learn a whole new set of things that contradict what we already learned. Kickstarter is pretty fluid; each campaign has a life of its own, and it can be nearly impossible to predict. Just plan as best you can. Sometimes it sucks and sometimes it’s awesome, but it is a fantastic way to bring your dreams to fruition. It is a means to an end, but it is perhaps the most personal and available platform for many makers and inventors. We hope it brings you much success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/09/10/kickstarter-part-1/&quot;&gt;POST 1&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/10/08/kickstarter-part-2/&quot;&gt;POST 2&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/11/12/kickstarter-part-3/&quot;&gt;POST 3&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;em&gt;POST 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/10/kickstarter-part-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/12/10/kickstarter-part-4/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hit Your Kickstarter Goal on Day 1 or Die Trying</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://livefreeandstart.com/crowdfunding/hit-your-kickstarter-goal/&quot;&gt;Live Fee and Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your campaign is now live, congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next 48 hours are going to be super hard and crazy. No doubt, you will have many moments of questioning how you ever got yourself into this mess. But hey, you did it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is the most important part: hit your goal on the first day, or die trying. Yes, you read that right. Your goal should be to raise all the money you asked for on day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, you ask? Because all Kickstarter campaigns show exactly where a project stands. There is this little green bar that shows how much of your funds you have raised. You will learn to loathe this little green bar. It shows people that your project either will be successful or will never be. If you get through the first 72 hours and your little green bar is still sitting at 10% full, you are in trouble. If it is 100% full, you are golden. People want to be part of successful projects, and that little green bar is the barometer they use to judge your campaign. The best way to mitigate this whole problem is just to fill the green bar fully on day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so what if you don’t get to 100% on day one? It’s not the end of the world. However, you will have a much bigger uphill climb during your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That also raises another question that we get asked a lot: How do I choose my funding goal? It is a tough one. It’s a balance of asking for just enough money that you realistically think you can get very early in your campaign. At the same time, you will be on the hook to make whatever it is you dreamed up, so make sure you have enough funding to do so. It’s impossible to answer this generically, so I would just recommend making sure you do your homework up-front to know what it will really cost to create your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 72 hours of any campaign is a firestorm of craziness. You need to be sending out emails to everyone you know, and ask them to share it with everyone they know. Basically, beg anyone you can find to give you money. Reach out to every reporter/journalist you can find and pitch your story. Ninety-nine percent of them will probably ignore you, but just keep plugging away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you hit the one-week mark, things will start to slow down. You will get fewer pledges per day and less media coverage. This is when you need to start attending those live events you planned out and doing cross-promotion. We usually look for similar or complimentary campaigns and reach out to them and see if they will share our project, and we will do the same. You can even have special deals although this can sometimes be logistically challenging. Either way, the next few weeks of your campaign will be grueling as you try to scrounge for more people, so have some things planned out. We usually send a weekly update to all the backers to keep them in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few days are when things go back to firestorm craziness. We like to attend a live event this last week to try and get as much promotion as possible. You can reach out to friends and family that were on the fence before or haven’t quite figured out how to use Kickstarter yet. Put fliers on cars and be creative. Do whatever you think will get the most traffic to your Kickstarter page. This is the time to be shameless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is especially important for you to know that once your campaign is over, you will never be able to change your campaign page again. So, if you need to make any last minute changes, do so before the clock hits zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, your campaign will be over, and you can sleep again without checking your backer count every five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re done, congratulations! Now the hard work really begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/09/10/kickstarter-part-1/&quot;&gt;POST 1&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/10/08/kickstarter-part-2/&quot;&gt;POST 2&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;em&gt;POST 3&lt;/em&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/12/10/kickstarter-part-4/&quot;&gt;POST 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/11/12/kickstarter-part-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/11/12/kickstarter-part-3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Steps to Kickstarter Success</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://livefreeandstart.com/crowdfunding/steps-to-kickstarter-success/&quot;&gt;Live Fee and Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we hope our first post didn’t scare you away from Kickstarter forever and that you are still ready to take the plunge and run your own campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If so, you are about to enter perhaps the hardest and most underestimated part, preparation. Most people just see the final product page and assume it was thrown together in a few days. In reality, most campaigns are the result of weeks or months of preparation. As we have now run three campaigns, we have a pretty decent plan that we follow, and we will lay that out for you. This is just our plan; feel free to pick and choose parts or tweak it however you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first task you need to do is pick a date to launch. While this seems easy, it is a critical first step. Your campaign should align with promotions and live events that you will attend while it is running, so you need to choose your dates carefully. Also, you need plenty of time to prep, so picking a date 6-8 weeks in the future should give you plenty of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have one more note about timing: pick a time that is relevant to your product. With our first campaign, we ended up trying to sell gloves in July, which wasn’t smart. We thought the gloves would ultimately be delivered in the winter, but that didn’t matter. People buy for immediate gratification, even if it means they receive the product when it doesn’t make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your date, you need to start building an email list. The best way to do this is to create a simple website with a sign-up form and try to drive as many people there as possible. Create Twitter, Facebook, Instagram and all other social media accounts, and push your website. Sign up on relevant forums and participate as well as promote; people want to trust your opinion in the area and not just see you pushing your products. Try to get as many people to your site and build up your reputation as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In parallel, you need to start filming your video. I can’t be more blunt about this: don’t make a crappy video. Hire a videographer. Find someone who has done this before and knows what they are doing. Yes, it will cost you money. Just know that the end product will be orders of magnitude better than if you let your cousin Sally do it because she has a nice camera. Hire a professional. Write the script. Walk through your shooting plan with them, and then let them edit. Look at other Kickstarter videos in the same category for inspiration. This whole process can easily take 4-6 weeks, so start planning early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, start putting together your Kickstarter page. We always outline it first and then start to fill in the text. If you need graphics, hire someone who can make them look professional. Again, this will cost you some money, but probably less than you would expect. Iterate your Kickstarter page as much as possible. There is a very good feedback system where you can share the page with people ahead of time. Use it! Send the link out to friends/ family and colleagues, and get feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week from your launch date, you should have your video done and your Kickstarter page mostly complete. You need to submit your project to Kickstarter for approval, something that can take days. Go ahead and get it submitted so you don’t miss your date. Don’t worry, you can still edit it afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, about seven days out is when you want to start building a buzz. This is when you start to use the email contact list you built by driving people to your landing page. Send out a status email and let them know you’re about to launch. Ask them to buy on the first day. Ask them to share with their friends and on social media. Get a buzz going!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get within a week of launch, you can also start to reach out to a few journalists and media contacts. You can usually find these people by looking at relevant publications in your field. Try to find people that write about similar things to what you have created. Reach out to them with a personalized email pitch. We have even shared the Kickstarter page early with certain contacts. Don’t reach out to too many right up front; focus on maybe 10-20 solid contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get to the eve of your launch, you need to push even harder. Once your project goes live, you want to hit your goal as fast as possible. Send out another email blast, send messages to friends/family, and post on all forums. You want a lot of people on the first day, so you need to line them up now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the time has come to launch: 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/09/10/kickstarter-part-1/&quot;&gt;POST 1&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;em&gt;POST 2&lt;/em&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/11/12/kickstarter-part-3/&quot;&gt;POST 3&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/12/10/kickstarter-part-4/&quot;&gt;POST 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/08/kickstarter-part-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/10/08/kickstarter-part-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kickstarter Sucks… Or Does It?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://livefreeandstart.com/crowdfunding/kickstarter-sucks-or-does-it/&quot;&gt;Live Fee and Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kickstarter sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, not really. It is actually an awesome, amazing platform where people can bring their ideas and aspirations and get them funded by many different people. Inventors and dreamers can then bypass the conventional funding routes of investors, bank loans, friends and family, and second mortgages to see their concepts brought to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should clarify that first sentence. Kickstarter is awesome! Running a Kickstarter campaign is what sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does it suck? Well, you basically have to take your entire dream, try to summarize it in a single web page, and then show it to thousands of people in hopes they will give you money. It is stressful, it is emotional, and it is hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are unfamiliar, Kickstarter is a platform where people can post any project and ask for money. They must give you something in return, but that is one of the only rules. The request may include pre-ordering the newest gadget, investing in a movie, watching someone create a new charity, or anything in between. The project creator sets a certain fundraising goal in dollars, and they must raise that amount or they get none of the money pledged. The idea is simple; many people can contribute a small amount to a project to raise enough money for the project to succeed. Easy, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, no. Running a campaign is a tremendous amount of work and can take many more hours than you thought possible. It is the culmination of months of preparation ahead of time, including acquiring funding for important items like graphics, videos, and photo shoots. It is then followed by pure craziness as your campaign progresses. You try to hit your goal early and then build on the momentum. Finally, you have to deliver. You owe those people something, and you need to make sure they get what they paid for or your dream is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is the introduction to a series of articles where we will try to help you through these waters should you ever try to navigate them. We are not experts, and if we are sure of one thing, it’s that no one is. We have run three Kickstarter campaigns, two of which have been successful and one that wasn’t. With the two successful campaigns, we raised over $100,000; I can assure you, that is not enough to make anyone’s dreams come true. People sometimes hear about Kickstarter campaign raising millions of dollars, but they are very few and very far between (and usually involve large investors beforehand).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following posts, we will try to lay out the blueprint of what we have learned along our Kickstarter journey. We have run campaigns for various products, so this advice may or may not apply to yours. Still, it is what we have learned and what has worked for us. We are hoping it can help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kickstarter can be hard, grueling, and crazy. It is also extremely liberating. In the end, you can realize your dreams without answering to investors. The community surrounding many of these projects is simply amazing; it is a group of people who genuinely want to help others. Through Kickstarter, you will gain more product and market knowledge than you could ever possibly do through any other means. In short: it sucks, but it’s awesome. We hope our advice brings you more of the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;POST 1&lt;/em&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/10/08/kickstarter-part-2/&quot;&gt;POST 2&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/11/12/kickstarter-part-3/&quot;&gt;POST 3&lt;/a&gt;  |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eric-ely.com/2015/12/10/kickstarter-part-4/&quot;&gt;POST 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/10/kickstarter-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/10/kickstarter-part-1/</guid>
      </item>
    

    
      
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>About</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the semi-personal blog of Eric Ely. I am a professional software developer and entrepreneur, working at and
starting my own various companies. This site will be my person al brain dump.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/about.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>